My name is Lilian Okoro.
Same University of Calabar, Nigeria.
And my topic is closely related to
what just happened
when this session began.
You see a lot of struggles connecting,
a lot of challenges with infrastructure.
And so my topic is
”Unsupervised
Pedagogy
and Electronic Literature
under Infrastructural
Constraint: Experiences from Calabar.”
Yeah, you already know
my name and [sound glitching] come in
different shades and
colors.
And in Nigeria,
when you hear, “Up NEPA!,” it's a common
challenge that we have come to embrace.
And when you talk about
electronic literature,
power and Internet
are key elements that must make
electronic literature possible.
And so I came up with
the concept of unsupervised pedagogy
[sound
glitching]
teaching my students
electronic literature.
The stage here now is power.
The screen goes off;
what happens to the learners?
What becomes of that
particular session of learning?
I have come to realize
that the learning shouldn't
stop when there's a power outage,
when there's Internet
disconnection,
the learners have to be equipped,
keep creating.
Even during these
infrastructural constraints.
And that every performance begins
with a moment of uncertainty
like we started now
and we are— and all that.
Sometimes the light itself fails and
sometimes the stage changes unexpectedly.
Yet the show must go on.
That is the slogan in the theatre.
So when these things happen,
what equips the students
to continue to create
is what I call the Calabar
model of unsupervised pedagogy.
C is create authentic projects
for the learners,
create projects
they can relate with, Then A,
assign collaborative
production roles.
Let students be paired
to reason together and assigned to create.
Then lead them through building on
different levels of reasoning.
I say lead through scaffolding,
then adapt through improvization.
You must learn to improvise
when what you need is not available.
Then you create from your mind
what should be present
until what you need is available.
It may be your Internet, it may be power.
Then build peer learning communities.
Let the students work in groups
where they can criticize
the ideas that come up,
either from the lecturer
or from themselves.
Then assign them to reflect.
Finally, R, reinforce learner autonomy.
When we do this during infrastructural
constraint, the learning is not paused.
Learning continues.
The students continue to exchange ideas
and eventually
the level of production is not reduced.
Because once power is restored,
once Internet is restored,
what has been generated in their mind,
their imagination,
shouldn't be paused
when electricity stops.
So electronic literature production begins
with teaching
and learning—
that is, pedagogy—before technology.
From this, so many things have emerged
and we see that the
students even reason more
flexibly when
they are a bit constrained
You see the [sound glitching]
before
even generating ideas from—
So the pause should— power
outbreak, what— this song will always come
up, “keep pushing.”
The show must go on
so students must keep learning.
They must keep creating even when
there are infrastructural constraints.
Once the teacher is able
to give the right information,
the right
creative nuggets to the learners,
it exposes them
to also exercise their mind,
not confining them to what the teacher
has, you know, positioned.
It gives them the leverage
to also use their mind while
they are paused.
And when they come back, they usually come
back stronger.
And some of the very outstanding
literature that my students have recorded
or have produced
come from when there is a pause,
when there is a breakdown
in either Internet or power.
So we shouldn't see the challenge of
infrastructural constraint as something
that should limit the Global South
from producing electronic literature.
We should see it as an opportunity
to explore the unsupervised pedagogy,
by preparing the students
to become creators, rather
than passive recipients of knowledge.
Every electronic literature comes
from a creative mind
that has been prepared,
and this preparation can come
even when the class is dark.
When electricity and Internet
become unavailable,
the creative process should not stop.
We must encourage ourselves to reorganize
into small groups,
continue writing, continue
producing these electronic literatures
until such a time
when these infrastructural
constraints are under control.
When infrastructure pauses,
production should not pause.
Unsupervised pedagogy prevents
creativity from pausing.
The show must go on,
always.
Thank you.